<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>publications on Aline R. de Carvalho</title>
    <link>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/categories/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in publications on Aline R. de Carvalho</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ardcarvalho.github.io/categories/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stable isotope insights into microplastic contamination within freshwater food webs</title>
      <link>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/post/article_sia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/post/article_sia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We quantified the trophic niche of individuals (macroinvertebrates and fish) to investigate the correlation with the microplastic concentration and features presented in their body - intestinal tract (for fish). We also compared the microplastic pollution (abiotic compartment) and the microplastic contamination (biotic contamination).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urbanization and hydrological conditions drive the spatial and temporal variability of microplastic polution</title>
      <link>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/post/article_st/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/post/article_st/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this high spatial and temporal resolution study, we resumed the environmental variables (through PCA) that could affect the variability of environmental microplastic pollution. Then, we investigated the environmental drivers, by mixed effect models, of the spatial and temporal variability in microplastic pollution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging use of thermo analytical methods coupled with MS for the quantification of micro(nano plastics)</title>
      <link>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/post/article_reviewpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/post/article_reviewpy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this review, we explore several methodological aspects to be considered for the development of themo analytical methods for the detection and quantification of micro(nano) plastics in environmental samples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MicroplaStream: Protocol for microplastic pollution monitoring in freshwater ecosystems</title>
      <link>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/post/article_microplastream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/post/article_microplastream/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this publication we share the protocol that we validated and applied in our studies of microplastic pollution in freshwater ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microplastic in angling baits as a cryptic source of contamination</title>
      <link>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/post/article_baits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/post/article_baits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Collaboration with researches from Bournemouth University (UK), we investigate the contamination of angling baits with microplastic particles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zebrafish water tank model (ZWT): a tool for human-like metabolism studies</title>
      <link>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/post/zwt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ardcarvalho.github.io/post/zwt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zebrafish (&lt;em&gt;Danio rerio&lt;/em&gt;) water tank (ZWT) approach was investigated as an alternative model for metabolism studies, based on six different experiments with four model compounds. Also, we were interested on the impact of steroid hormones on the endogenous metabolism of zebrafish. We discuss the appropriate conditions, merits, and relevant limitations to conduct ZWT experiments for the investigation of drug metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
